William Ley

Washington, DC, 20009 | 202-489-6540 | will.ley@madhatter.dev | GitHub | Blog | Portfolio Website | LinkedIn

FULL STACK SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Full stack software engineer with a passion for building community and improving communication through technology. With experience in Ruby on Rails, JavaScript, and React and a background in diversity, equity, and inclusion work, I first came to web development through a desire to create in new ways and connect people across cultures and backgrounds. I bring strong skills in writing clear, clean, and well-tested code, managing multiple projects to deadline, and understand the work ethic needed to meet the challenges of a distributed and asynchronous team in a collaborative environment.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

JavaScript, React, Redux, Thunk, Sagas, Node.js, Express, TypeScript, Jest, Enzyme, HTML5, CSS, CSS-in-JS, CSS Grid, Ruby, Ruby on Rails, Rspec, Python, Flask, Pytest, REST, PostgreSQL, SQL, MapBoxGL, VectorWorks, Git, Figma

TECHNICAL PROJECTS

Fantasy Baseball App -Video Walkthrough

A custom app for the Coqui Fantasy Baseball League

- Automatically lock-in playable teams at a given time
- Team owners can trade players between each other and free agents
- Admin panel to allow for management and creation of seasons and owners
- Built with Semantic UI React, React/Redux/Sagas, Node.js(Express), TypeScript, Socket.io, and CSS Grid

WeRHere - GitHub | Heroku

A web app for people experiencing homelessness which works both on and off line

- Uses MapBoxGL for display and interaction with geolocation data
- Incorporates 14 DC.gov Open Data APIs to put many of the city's resources together on one platform
- Built with Semantic UI React, React/Redux/Thunk, and CSS Grid

Flatiron Students Connect - GitHub | Heroku

A platform for students to take and easily share notes and online references

- Uses React as a gateway for dynamic page management
- Includes Redux and Thunk for state management and component flexibility and JWT token auth
- Supported by Rails as an API to manage integration with Postgres
- Persisted with Postgres and hosted on Heroku

EXPERIENCE

Freelance Full Stack Developer

Full Stack Development of custom applications

Washington, DC 10/2019 - Present

Flatiron School

Washington, DC 10/2018 - 09/2019

Software Engineering Coach

Developed a React Interface with a Rails API for an existing student-pairing application providing a more informative

- and intuitive user experience • Taught, built, and modified existing curriculum for Ruby, Sinatra, Ruby on Rails, JavaScript, React, and Redux;
- Graduated seven cohorts
- Collaborated and lead code-based marking events for over 40 participants, pair programed with the engineering team building a Slack bot
- Interviewed potential students from all over the world on a distributed team

Georgetown Day School

Washington, DC

Diversity, Equity, and Inclusion Teacher (9th grade Seminar)

09/2009 - 06/2018

- Facilitated social justice discussions around subjects such as race, religion, sexual orientation, gender, and socioeconomic status
- Collaboratively developed curriculum on a cross departmental team

EDUCATION

Flatiron School 06/2018 - 09/2018

Full Stack Web Development, Ruby on Rails and JavaScript program

Boston University, Boston, MA

Bachelor of Arts, English 05/2000